上方不太稳固
Brace gonna be tricky
必须弄些支撑物来 不然会塌方
Must get the tunnel properly supported or it will come down to our heads.
苏珊 将会找你要信息
Susan will call you for information
让她来接你 然后进她的车
Make sure sure she picked you up, and get in the car , all right?
这么急电话约你出来
Eager to call you up
我想你会感兴趣知道这个消息的
Just thought what you want to know
如果你真要走的话
If you really leaving,
请带上我 求你了 我不想待这了
Take me with you, please. I dont want to be here anymore.
你还是不参与的好
You dont want to get inpart with this.
我也无法想信他不和他们合作
There is a part of me that I dont believe he doesnt work with them.
但他是我所爱的人
Cause he is the man I love.
他还要带我去巴黎 我的初行
The man is going to take me to my first trip to Paris.
他不会带你去 我会
If he doesnt take you, I will.
真是令人惊叹啊 看着吧
Impressive blanco, enjoy it
少了后顾之忧了
Now we can settle this back
我们有24个小时来挖隧道
All right, we got 24 hours to dig that tunnel
照这个样子 得用上3天
You mean you want to take our guys three days to dig it first time
这么说吧 即使真的挖好了
Let's just say by some America
接下来又如何呢?
We are able to park the dirt,then what?
有办法对付塔楼卫兵?
Have plans to get rid of guards tower?
迈克 惠斯勒说
Michael Mr. Whistler here says
得停停了
You know you got stop less time by clock
我会想办法的
I am still working on that
那女人会忍忍再多给时间 甚至给我们买喝的
I like to know this girl could put up with spend any more time and buy us some drinks
我也同意 迈克 大家都累了
I agreed Michael. You know we are all out of energy
我说了这样不行
I just say there is no better.
我说就这样吧
I dont give nos what
大家都忙得散架了还怎么出去?
How could we get out of this hell everyone gonna fall apart
你来么?
You come?
今天不行
Not today.
詹姆斯和我还有很多事要澄清
James and I got a lot things to clean up
但是我不会逼着他这么做
But I dont trying to do with
你有想过要是能回到过去么
You ever wish that you could back time?
想想过去那些有意义的事情
Just remember how I was things make sense
故去三年的每一天
Everyday for last three years.
那是惠斯勒的女友?
Is that Whistler's girlfriend?
她为什么呆在车里?
Why she's staying in the car?
因为她以为要明天才能见你
Cause she think she will see you tomorrow.
你还期待着我们有足够的时间?
It's expecting we have time you getting on
此话怎讲?
And?
你肯定吗?
You sure that was?
我们进展如何?
Where are we?
落后进度 明午后我们应该可以出去
Behind schedule, we should be on the same side by tomorrow afternoon.
你说应该是什么意思?
What do you mean should?
地道应该把我们送去禁入区
The tunnel get us into no mans land,
但却有栅栏 我们需要改道避开塔卫
but it get the fence, we're going need new diversion for the tower guards.
什么时候
What time?
最好还是白天行动
Daytime's still our best option.
晚上他们会加强防卫
They double the guards at night.
还有吉普车巡逻?
And the jeep patrols?
是的 呃 还有些别的
Yeah. and, uh there's something else.
什么
What?
蒂博格加入了 还有马宏
T-bag's coming. and Mahone.
还有贝里克 还有一个毒贩子
Bellick. oh, yeah, there's a drug lord, too.
知道么? 跟他们无关
You know what? it's not about them.
关键是惠斯勒 我们得尽一切办法
It's about Whistler. we got to do whatever
你不必知道惠斯勒究竟是什么人
You don't need to know who Whistler is.
那他有多大价值你知道吧 我儿子的命
What about what he's worth? my son's life.
惠斯勒并不是解决问题的办法
I justish there was another way to do this.
要救出lj 但不能把惠斯勒交给他们
To save lj without handing Whistler over.
听着 我们没的选择
Look, man, that's it. there isn't.
我知道
I know.
听着 你解决隧道的问题
Listen, you worry about the tunnel,
我会解决守卫的问题
I worry about the guards.
-明天见 -明天见
See you tomorrow. tomorrow.
那些柱子 就尽量用吧
Hey, now, don't skimp on the braces up there.
如果还要的话 就只管
In fact, if you want to add a little extra, just
这活要干到什么时候啊
You know, we can work on this railroad all
不过没关系
The livelong day, but it don't matter
反正斯科菲尔德不知道出去后会怎么个情况
If Scofield doesn't know what happens once
一旦我们出去
We get off the train. once we get
大家就各顾各的
Out of here, it's every man for himself.
斯科菲尔德不用对我们任何人负责
Scofield's not responsible for any of us.
是吗?
Is that so?
显然你还不了解他
You obviously don't know him very well,
大老粗
Shakespeare.
当我们从福克斯河逃出来后
When we broke out of fox river,
他想把我们都给毁了
He tried to screw every one of us.
有一半的人
Half the men ended up either
要么被杀 要么被抓 或者更糟
Dead, captured or worse.
最容易被逮到的人
The guys who are easiest to catch
就是那些四处惹事或者整天哀叹
Are the one's who spend more time
而不赶紧逃跑的人
Pissing and moaning at each other than running.
给你的唯一建议是
My only advice to you,
传道书第六章13节
Ecclesiastes 6:13.
不要使你自己和你的敌人混在一起
"separate thyself from thy enemies,
多注意下你的朋友
And take heed of thy friends."
干的怎样了 阿历克斯?
How we doing, Alex?
如果那些柱子能撑的住的话
Well, if those braces hold,
明天的某个时候
We could be to the surface
我们就能到上面了
Sometime tomorrow.
都动动 大家都要保持清醒
Let's rotate. keep everybody fresh.
欢迎进入矿坑 小白脸
Welcome to the coal mine, canary.
浇什么水啊
Drop what?
别老让你的汗滴到我身上
Don't drop your body-water upon me like that
不是我的汗 我发誓
Hey, it ain't coming from me, I swear.
工程师 过来
Engineer, come.
你看看
Look at this.
是碰到水管了还是怎么的?
We hit a pipe or something?
哦 不妙
Oh, no.
那正好是我们隧道的上方
That's right above our tunnel.
撑不到明天了
That's not going to hold till tomorrow.
该怎么办?
So what do we do?
今晚就走
We leave tonight.
今晚?
Tonight?
你不是说过晚上不可能成功
I thought you said a nighttime escape was impossible.
如果继续下雨 隧道又会坍塌
If the rain keeps up, the tunnel will collapse again,
到时就前功尽弃了
And that'll be the end of it.
你就死定了
It'll be the end for you.
时间不多的人是你
You're the one on a deadline.
那万一在我们出去的时候坍塌呢?
What if it gives out whilwe're inside?
我们岂不是都被活埋了
We end up like buried treasure.
要不想去 那就滚
You want out, get out
听着 要是没有大家齐心协力
Look, you're not pulling this off tonight
你今晚也出不去
Without all of us working around the clock.
同样的 没有他的计划
And none of us
我们大家也都出不去
Are ever making it out of here
所以 如果你能够
Without his plan, so if you tell me
想出一个今晚出去的办法
That you can figure out a way how to do this at night,
那么我们都会和你一起努力
Then i we can figure out a way
想办法及时挖好隧道
How to get that tunnel dug in time.
开始挖吧
Let's start digging.
你是不是掉了东西
I think you dropped something.
我在旧报纸上读到了
I've read in old newspapers that make it to sona
美国人是如何要别人去遵守自己所丢弃的标准
How americans hold others to standards they ignore.
美国人认为别人都不该有权力 除了他们自己
How they think no one should have power but them.
我告诉别人 这不是真的 但其实就是真的
I tell everyone it's a lie, but I see it's true.
我知道你要走了
I know you're leaving.
那我想 我为你做了那么多
And I think that after everything I've done to help,
你居然不带上我 你太无耻了
I think it sucks you're not taking me with you
我知道你现在不明白
I know it doesn't seem like it now,
但其实我是在帮你 送了你一份大礼
But I'm doing you a favor. I'm giving you a gift.
让我继续呆在大牢 是吧
Oh, wow, life in prison.
谢谢了 真是得偿所愿啊
Thank you. I've always wanted one of those.
这比四处逃亡要好
It's better than a life on the run.
我不属于这 我只不过
I don't belong here. all I did was give a guy
你留在这
You're not going
对不起
I'm sorry.
为了你好
It's for the best.
你怎么知道这是为了我好?
How do you know what's best for me?
都办好了?
Y cuanto me va costar?
好 谢谢
Okay, muchas gracias.
准备好了
It's good to go.
你知道时间和地点 是吧?
You know where and when to be, right?
如果你不准时出现 我们就玩完了
If you're not there, we're screwed.
你没事吧?
You all right?
我很好
I'm fine.
我来取下东西
I'm just going to grab my stuff.
是啊 或许对你和詹姆斯来说 消失是最好的了
Yeah. probably best if you and James disappear.
我知道
I know. I know.
知道在哪见面 是吧?
You know where to meet us, right?
普拉亚布兰克镇 你会在
Playa blanca. you'll be on the
3-12
3-12.
3-12 那明天见
3-12. we'll see you tomorrow then.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你也是
You, too.
又是苏珊那娘们
Hey, it's that Susan chick.
她又找我了
She wants to meet again.
好的
Good.
告诉她一切正常
Let her know everything's on track.
让她尽可能感到踏实
We want to make her feel as comfortable as possible.
她为何会不踏实?
Why shouldn't she be?
她明天就能得到她要的人了 是吧?
She's going to get her guy tomorrow, right?
是的 只要迈克的良知不惹麻烦的话
Well, if Michael's conscience doesn't get in the way.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
他有顾虑
He's having doubts.
关于是否能够尽快逃走
About if he can pull it off?
如果必要的话
About if he should.
但是他一定可以成功的 是吧?
But he's going to go through with it, right?
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
找给索纳监狱外部的灯供电的电线
Where the power lines connect to Sona's exterior lights.
如果切除电源以后会有逃亡的机会
If cutting the power out there was an option,
为什么我们没有一开始就这样做
Why didn't we do that in the first place?
首先 那里的电源不是这里所能控制的
One, the power out there isn't controlled from in here.
其次 还有那个东西
And, two, there's that.
每个监狱都有一个后备的发电机
Every prison has a backup generator.
就算我们切断了电源 它们还会再亮
Even if we cut the lights, they'll just come back on again
立刻
Immediately.
好吧 这是一个严肃和残酷的问题
Well, that's a big, bloody problem.
告诉勒齐我需要他的电话
Tell Lechero I need his phone.
计划有变 林肯
Change of plans, Linc.
我们今晚行动
We're doing this tonight.
今晚? 发生了什么事情 迈克
Tonight? what happened, Michael?
雨 泥土 地道 都是问题
Rain, dirt, tunnel, problem.
-地道还能支持多久? -看情况
How long can it hold?
那要看情况了
That depends
看什么情况?
Depends on what?
根据雨停的时间
When the rain stops.
你说过晚上越狱是不可能的
You said breaking out at night was impossible.
是说过 不过
Yeah, well
告诉我你想怎么摆平这个问题
You want to tell me how you're going to pull this off?
首先 我需要苏克雷的帮助
For starters, I need to get ahold of Sucre.
苏克雷 你知道我干什么谋生吗
Sucre, do you know what I do for a living?
我有一个好主意
I have a pretty good idea.
我能读懂人
I read people.
而且你 我的朋友 像是一本多彩的书
And you, my friend, are a coloring book.
我觉得
I think you left
你把这个掉到我的车里了
This in my car.
这个只是 我的意思是
Look. that that was just I mean
不用解释
No. no, no, no, no.
是我的错
My fault.
我猜我给你布置任务的时候
I guess I just didn't make myself clear
你没有听懂
When I laid out the terms of our arrangement.
所以我现在得再尽可能简洁的讲一次
So I'm going to try again as simply as I know how.
如果有任何事发生
Anything happens
只要是我不希望发生的事情
Anything at all that I wasn't expecting
那么芝加哥就会少一个
And there will be one less
怀孕的女孩
Pregnant girl in chicago.
你看 迈克和林肯什么也没告诉我
Look, Michael and Lincoln don't tell me everything.
费尔南多这是你最后一次机会了
Fernando, this is your last chance.
只要你说是或者不是
I want a yes or a no.
那兄弟两人是不是将要把惠斯勒带出索纳
Are the brothers gonna break Whistler out of Sona?
是的
Yes.
而且他们打算把他交给我?
Are they planning on handing him over to me?
是的
Yes.
你希望我先打中玛丽克鲁兹哪个部位?
Where do you want me to shoot Maricruz first,
打后脑还是臀部?
In the bun or in the oven?
好吧
Okay
我听说一件事情
There's one thing I heard.
是关于迈克的事情 他对 惠斯勒有些担心
It's Michael. he's, he's having some concerns about Whistler.
担心他什么?
What kind of concerns?
关于把他交给你的事情
About handing him over.
你得知道
You got to understand,
上次他越狱带出了一群坏蛋
He broke out some pretty bad guys last time.
我想他自今都没有原谅自己
I think he's never forgiven himself for that.
他打算把惠斯勒留下?
He's planning on leaving him behind?
可能吧 我不知道
Maybe. I don't know.
嘘
Shh.
你好 林肯
Hello, Lincoln.
今晚就要行动了
It's going down tonight.
今晚?
Tonight?
我应该担心吗
Should I be worried?
我一收到消息就打给你了
I called you first thing.
我说的全是真的
I'm being straight up with you.
这真是令人高兴
That's refreshing.
那晚上见
So I'll see you tonight.
你对我坦诚 我也会坦诚待你
You show me yours and I'll show you mine.
今晚就要行动了
It'soing down tonight.
你知道吗
Do you know about that?
我发誓我不知道
I didn't know, I swear.
滚出去
Get out of here.
怎么样了?
How'd it go?
她找到那个炸弹了 林肯
She found the bomb, Linc.
那个我们丢在她车里的
The one we put in her car.
她怎么找到的 苏克雷
How did she find the bomb, Sucre?
我不知道 兄弟 对不起
I don't know, bro. I'm sorry.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
今后我会补偿的
Look, I'llak mit
我发誓
Up to you, I swear.
你可以开始了
You can start now.
迈克在索纳遇到一点麻烦
Michael's in a bit of trouble in Sona.
什么样的麻烦?
What kind of trouble?
雨停了 这是不是意味着 ?
The rain stopped. does that mean ?
不行 已经对隧道造成了损坏
No. the damage is done.
我们不能冒险等着
We can't risk waiting.
有什么有趣的事情吗
Anything interesting?
比如一些公司想要染指的
Like some coordinates
坐标
The company might want to get their hands on?
如果他们不想让我出去
If they didn't want me out of here
而且你的侄儿是安全的 你还会这样做吗?
And yourephew was safe, would you still be doing this?
越狱?
Breaking out?
不会
No.
为什么在有机会自由的时候你仍选择留下呢
Why would you choose to stay if there was a chance at freedom?
我认为这就是我们之间的区别
Well, I guess that's the difference between us.
我愿意偿还我犯下的罪
I'm willing to pay for my sins.
你认为我不愿意?
And I'm not?
这是个不错的问题
That's a good question.
水进来的很快 同志
Water's coming down pretty fast up in here, patron.
是啊 我们必须得快点挖
Yeah. we hav to dig faster.
我一直在想
You know, I've been thinking.
我们都不应该各为自己
It doesn't have to be every man for himself.
你和我可以互相帮助
You and I can help each other.
我更愿意找有2个手的助手
If I need a hand, I'll find someone with a spare.
好吧 我确实
While it's true I may be lacking
在某一方面少些东西
Something inhe west,
不过我会在另一方面弥补
I more than make up for it in the north.
考虑一下吧
Think about it.
斯科菲尔德让我们到这里来做苦力 奴工
Scofield's got us down here doing manual labor; slave labor.
我不是奴工
I ain't no slave.
我是为自己做的
I'm doing this for me.
你觉得 斯科菲尔德在上面干什么
Why do you think Scofield's up there
在我们做这些的时候
And we'rdoe here?
他正在计划一些事情
He's planning something.
我们中间谁没有自己的打算?
Who among us isn't?
那是什么
What the hell is that?
好吧 我们就卸在这边
Ok, let's unload it here.
帮忙把车推出这块泥潭
Make the animals walk through the filth
过来
Come here.
一起推
Let's go.
很好 走起来
Good. Good Keep going
没事了
We're good.
我们安全了
We are all right.
对
Yeah.
你好 林肯 好久不见
Hello, Lincoln. long time no see.
还没有多久
Not long enough.
我在想
I was thinking that we could
我们可以私下聊聊
Have a little chat in person.
确保我们对于今晚发生的事情
Make sure we're all on the same page
是同步的
About what's gonna happen tonight.
好的
All right.
30分钟后 在这个地方 我会给你发消息
30 minutes, this location. I'm sending a text.
对不起 什么事?
Sorry. What's up?
今天是发薪日
It's payday.
你第一个发薪日
You're first
你得去领取支票
You need to pick up your check.
是的 多谢了
Ah si si glacia
稍后见
See you later.
-你好 -嘿 是我
Hello. hey, papi, it's me.
嘿
Hey.
林肯说你需要点帮助
Lincoln said you needed some help.
你对电源了解多少?
How much do you know about electricity?
嘿 你回来啦
Hey, you're back.
我实在觉得独自在这下面不太舒服
I'm not real comfortable being alone down here with those
那是什么?
What's that?
掩护 亲爱的 和一些泥浆
Syrup; honey. make a little pile of dirt.
把泥土凝结起来
Gather some dirt.
斯科菲尔德说我们出去以后
Scofield said we got to make
必须找个东西掩盖洞口
Something to cover the hole once we get out.
当灯光再亮起来的时候
So when the lights go back on
就会象没有人离开过那一样
It's gonna look like nobody ever left.
快干 把泥土和匀
Go ahead. spread it around.
我在想
I was thinking
我们应该是一起的 你知道吧?
We should be a team, yoknow?
不只在越狱过程中 以后也是
Not just during the escape, but after.
就像Butch和Sundance(来自一美国电影的好朋友)
Like, like Butch and Sundance.
Butch和Sundance死了
Butch and sundance died.
我的意思是在别的方面类似
Well, I mean in the other parts.
我有个主意
Here's an idea.
我们先按斯科菲尔德的计划做
We go along with Scofield's plan,
然后等大家都停下来
And then when everyone stops
休息时 我们就抓住他们
To take a breath, we grab 'em,
布鲁斯 斯科菲尔德 蒂博格
Burroughs, Scofield, Bagwell.
带他们回去接受指控
We take 'em back home to face charges.
我们就成英雄了
Hell, we'd be heroes.
说不定还能写本书
Might even get a book deal.
阿历克斯 我们可以一起写书
We could write it together, Alex.
-怎么样? -卖书?
How'd that be? a book deal?
是的 她在
Yeah.
布拉德 这样你就满足了?
Gonna make you happy, Brad?
你有更好的主意?
You got a better idea?
没错
Yeah, I do.
你是指和老婆孩子一起?
Something to do with a wife and kid?
对 差不多
Yeah, something like that.
还有多余的位置给我吗?
You got room for one more?
快 阿历克斯
Come on, Alex.
像我这样的人会怎么做?
What's a guy like me gonna do?
还是先逃出这里再说吧
Let's just let scofield get us out of here,
然后我们再慢慢盘算这些 好吗
And then we'll worry about everything else, all right?
好
All right.
快 再多一点泥土
Come on. a little more dirt.
仔细听着 按我说的做
Listen very carefully and do exactly as I tell you.
你确定不想让林肯做这个?
You sure you don't want Linc to do this?
他懂的比我懂的多
He knows more about this than I do.
这不是谁懂的多的问题
It's not about what you know.
而是你在哪工作的问题
It's about where you work.
既然进了索纳工作 朋友
And as a Sona employee, my friend,
唯一一个不被射杀的原因
You have the unique ability of not getting shot
就是在这里工作
For being here.
你看见那座行政楼了吗
You see the admin building?
看见了
I see it.
进去后往左
Go to it and make a left.
进去往左 明白
To it and left. got it.
另外一边有一条小道
On the other side is a berm.
那里应该有个金属柜
There should be a metal cage.
就是备用电力系统
That's the backup generator.
好 明白了
Okay, I see it.
别让塔楼的警卫看到你离的太近
Don't let the tower guard see you get too close.
表现正常一点就行
Just act casual.
听到我说 开始
When I say now,
你就赶紧跑过去躲到后面
You run and duck behind it.
快到了
Almost.
等等
Hold on.
开始
Now
好了
Okay.
好了 在底部
Okay. there should be
应该有铭牌
Some writing near the bottom.
我要知道生产商的名字
I need the name of the manufacturer,
以及设备型号 序列号等 所以一切
Make and model number, anything.
好 好的
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
我明白了
I got it, I got it.
是 是普拉纳工业公司
It's, uh, it's, uh, Prana Industrial.
型号是3210
Model number 3210.
3210 有客户服务电话吗
3210. is there a customer service number?
1-800-555-1212
1-800-555-1212.
好 谢了 这些就是我要的
All right. thanks. that's all I need.
你真的认为今晚能得手吗
You really think you can pull this off tonight?
你真的想知道吗
You want to know the tth?
不 我只是想知道一切都在掌握之中
No, I just want all of it go down smooth.
大家都能得到自己想要的
For everyone to get what they want.
是的 我能做到
Yeah, I do.
听着 就算能够搞定这些灯光
Listen, even if you get this worked out with the lights,
你打算怎么对付那些巡逻车
What are you gonna do about the jeep patrols?
我们必须要冒这个险
We're just gonna have to take our chances.
也许不用了
Maybe you don't.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
LJ在哪?
Where's lj?
安全的地方 放松点
Somewhere safe. take a load off.
要来杯喝的吗
Can I offer you a drink?
苏珊 什么事
What's going on, Susan?
我只是想让大家一起
I just wanted to get everyone together
来商量一下今晚的安排
So we can discuss tonight's agenda.
或者制订个手册
Maybe nail down a few guidelines.
还是和原来的一样 没有变化
It's the same as before, nothing has changed.
事实上 我在想
Actually, I was thinking
我们应该带上所有的参与者
We should probably include all the players.
对吗
Don't you?
你来干吗
What are you doing in here?
放哨
Just keeping watch.
确保没人去下面
Make sure nobody tries to get down to the tunnel.
你在联系谁?
Who are you calling?
你好 请问是客户服务吗?
Yeah, hi. is this, uh, customer service?
是 我是
Yeah, I'm, uh
我是在巴拿马做建筑工程项目的
I'm a sub working, building down here in panama,
我刚接到一个客户电话
And, um, we got a clntien-site.
他们问了一些关于
They're asking questions
我们安装的3210型号的发电机
About the 3210 generator we're installing.
对 没错
Yeah. exactly. um
他们想知道 如果关掉主电源
Anyway, they want to know, if the main power shuts down,
这个发电机会在多久后
How long are they gonna be in the dark,
恢复电力?
Um, before the generator kicks in?
好的 谢谢
Yeah. thanks.
我在线等
I'll hold.
你真是个说谎高手
You're a very good liar.
就是这个?
That's the timing?
不 这是
No, that's, uh
就这些
That's it.
非常感谢
Appreciate it.
怎么样?
Well?
我们能搞定
We gonna make it
我们应该有
We should have
刚好够的时间逃走
Just enough dark to make it out.
所有人一起?
With everyone?
你和惠斯勒在一起?
You with Whistler?
是
Yes.
苏珊有话要说
Susan has got a message.
为什么 让他接
Why? put him on.
是给你的
It's for you.
你好
Yes?
好的 我去找他 什么现在
All right, I got him. what now?
告诉他 我要他仔细听好
Tell him I want him to listen
接下来的指示
Very carefully to the following instructions.
她要你仔细听
She wants you to listen real care
我听到了
I can hear.
什么指示
Instructions about what?
詹姆斯
James?
是索菲亚吗 她在吗
Was that Sofia? is she there?
是的
Yeah.
怎么回事
What's going on?
他想知道是怎么回事
He wants to know what this is about.
好吧
All right.
我会告诉他
I'll tell him.
不
No
刚 刚刚是
Was was that just
是索菲亚吗
Is that Sofia?
是索菲亚吗?
你有计算出
Have you figured out
正确的坐标了吗 詹姆斯
The coordinates yet, James?
求你了
Please.
差不多了
Almost.
你没有
Wrong answer.
不
No
我们出来后 我会帮你找到他们的
I'll get them for you when we get out
我发誓
Of here, I swear.
所有你的承诺 你的保证
All your promises, your guarantees
都是狗屎
They mean nothing.
我已经给了充足的时间你们了
I'm pretty sick of waiting around for you boys
充足的让我都要人头不保了
To screw me over.
今天我必须得到这些坐标
I want those coordinates by the end of the day.
不
No
必须想个办法
Gotta figure it out.
必须做点什么
Gotta do something.
必须得做点什么了
我们都明白你不能就这样把坐标给他们
We both know that you can't just hand over that information.
为什么 为什么不能
Why? why can't i?
一旦他们得到他们想要的
Once they get what they want,
他们就没理由继续留着你了
They'll have no reason to keep you
以及你的女朋友和我的侄子
Or your girlfriend or my nephew alive.
那我要怎么做
So what do I do?
我 我
I, I just,
难道我就让他们折磨索菲亚
I just let them torture Sofia?
我们会想出办法的
We'll work something out.
我们会搞定的
We'll think it through.
我已经有办法了
I already have.
惠斯勒
Whistler
惠斯勒 他到底
Whistler. what is
有什么特别的
So special about him anyway, huh?
你认为他和那些想让
You think he has anything to do with why them people
斯科菲尔德死的人有什么关系吗
Wanted Scofield down here in the first place?
这不关我鸟事
It's really none of my business.
那什么是关你鸟事的 阿历克斯
What exactly is your business, Alex?
你现在想的
Something on your mind?
我只是说
I'm just saying
如果大家要这样讨价还价 互相猜疑
If we needed a bargaining chip,
你认为
Do you think
他真的会帮我们逃出去吗
A sharp stick in that dull limey would help us out?
不是我们
There is no"us."
你和我
You and me are a lot more
比你想像的更甚 阿历克斯
Alike than you think, Alex.
我们都知道那是什么感觉
We both know how it feels
失去一个挚爱的人
To lose a great love.
杀死一个人
How it feels to kill a man.
现在 我们都在这里玩完了 都是因为迈克・斯科菲尔德
And we both ended up in here because of Michael Scofield.
这将是个正义的惩罚方式
Wouldn't it be poetic justice if we could just
如果我们还给他
Return the favor?
正义?
Justice, huh?
如果这个世界上还有一点点正义的话
If there was an ounce of it left in this world
你就会和你家里其他人一样
You'd be lying face down in the same unmarked grave
躺在无名坟墓里
As the restof our inbred family.
我们之间唯一的不同 阿历克斯 就是徽章
The only difference between me and you, Alex, is a badge,
而且最后一次我发现 你根本就没有
And the last time I checked, you didn't even have that,
你可以继续期待你的幸福终点 阿历克斯
So you can just keep on hoping for your happy endings, Alex,
你可以继续蒙着眼罩向前
You just keep on plowing ahead with them blinders on,
但是那些眼罩是
You know, but the thing abouthem blinders is
很难让你向后看
It makes it really hard to watch your back.
一会儿就好了 我保证
It's gonna be better soon, I promise.
他是对的 如果詹姆斯
He's right, you know. if James loves you
真有他说的那样爱你 他会给我们想要的
The way he says he does, he'll give us what we want,
然后呢 你和你的白马王子
And then you and your white knight
就可以骑马而去了
Can ride off into the sunset.
除非你已经准备好要跟着他了
Unless you're already with him.
你害怕了 苏珊
You scared, Susan?
我看起来害怕了吗 林肯
Do I look scared, Lincoln?
拔出这样的东西
To pull something like this
你绝望了?
You desperate?
你最好别跟我作对了
You need to stop fighting with me.
如果你真的明白
If you really understood
究竟发生了什么 你就会知道
What was going on, you would know that
我们都不是坏人
We're not the bad guys.
不能耍我
Could've fooled me.
你就没有过
Haven't you ever done
为了一个正确的理由做错事吗
The wrong things for the right reason?
正确的理由是什么 苏珊
What are the right reasons, Susan?
惠斯勒为什么就那么重要
What is it abo Whistler that's so important.
我可以告诉你
I could tell you.
但是然后我就要杀了你
But then I'd have to kill you.
反正你不管怎么样都要那么做的
You're gonna do that anyway.
如果惠斯勒给我们想要的
Whistler gives us what we want,
也许我就不会了
Maybe I won't have to.
林肯来电话了
Linc called.
他们在路上了
They're on their way.
我搞定他们
I figured them out.
坐标
The coordinates.
我来处理
I'm gonna hand them over.
我想你应该知道
I thought you should know
所以你可以做好一切预防
So you can take whatever precautions you can.
如果
What if, uh
如果你给他们错的坐标
What if you give them the wrong coordinates.
这就会给我们赢得更多的时间
It might buy us some more time.
林肯就可以带索菲亚安全离开
Maybe Linc can get Sofia to safety.
就像他对莎拉一样
Like he did with Sara?
很抱歉
I'm sorry. i
我不是故意的
I didn't mean to.
我
I, uh
我只是不知道该做什么
I just don't know what else to do.
我做了不对
I'm damned if I do.
不做也不对
I'm damned if I don't.
不可能赢的
There's way to win.
这不是关于胜负了
It's not about winning anymore.
这是关于生存
It's about surviving
如果放弃了
Which is not the same
后果不同
As giving up.
但是你可以温文尔雅的走
But you can go gracefully.
很荣耀
There's honor.
去保护你爱的人
Protecting the ones you love.
荣耀太奢侈了 我们都负担不起
Honor's a luxury men like us can't afford.
你能跟我保证今晚一定会成功吗
Can you promise me we' llmake it out of here tonight?
不耍花样
No games.
你能真诚的跟我保证吗
Can you honestly promise me?
我可以跟你保证我会尽我所能
I can promise you I'll do everything in my power.
我希望那够用
I wish that were good enough.
如果你做了
If you do this
如果你给了那些他们想要的
If you give them what they want
就统统失败了 我们就什么都不是了
Everything that's been lost
怎么了
what's up?
没事儿的
take it easy
好的
okay
没问题
no problem
是的 我想要找孟赫斯警官 谢谢
yes,i'd like to speak to Officer Monjares,please
孟赫斯 有你的电话
hey Arturo -phone for you
我能跟你说几句话吗
can I talk to you for a minutes
我有点着急
I'm kind of hurry
我要去别的地方
I got some place to be
要去哪里
where's that
我的朋友今晚要走
Friends of mine are moving tonight
他们需要我的帮助
and they need my help
告诉他们你会晚点到
tell them you're gonna be late
我们走吧
Let's go
快走
walk
惠斯勒 有访客
Whistler,you have a visitor
whisler 有访客
whisler,you have a visitor
他要把东西给他们
He's gonna give it to them.
没事儿 我一分钟以后去看你
Relax. I'll see you in a minute.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
迈克・斯科菲尔德 有访客
Michael Scofield,you have a visitor
我猜
I suppose
现在这个时候自我介绍显得很重要
Introductions are unnecessary at this point.
你在这里干什么 格雷琴
What are we doing here, Gretchen?
我们来这里道别的
We're here to say good-bye.
我保证 亲爱的
I promise you, sweetheart,
他们不会再伤害你了
They're not going to hurt you anymore.
你有没有坐标 詹姆斯
Do you have the coordinates, James?
-有的 -很抱歉
Yes. I'm sorry.
我试着逃跑
I tried to run away
这不是你的错
This is not your fault.
是我的错
It's mine.
当我找了这个工作
When took this job,
我就知道他们不是好人
I knew they weren't good people.
我只是不知道他们有多坏
I just didn't know how bad they were.
一切都发生了
And everything that's happened
都是因为我
It's all because of me.
对此我非常抱歉
And for that I'm truly sorry.
坐标
The coordinates.
你就先忘了这些吧
Just pass them through.
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
我在买一些善意
I'm buying some goodwill.
你买了她的葬礼
You're buying her funeral.
你知道我手里有
You know I have
你们想要的 我会给你们剩下的部分
What you need.
然后我会给你剩下的部分
and then I'll give you the rest
但是只能在我了解到
But only after I know
索菲亚 lj
That Sofia, that lj,
还有站在这里的这些人
And that these men here
都安然无恙
they're all safe.
你听懂了吗
Do you understand me?
詹姆斯
James
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be all right.
我好感动噢
I'm impressed.
看上去渔夫也会玩煽情
It seems our fisheanrmgrew himself a
你真能以她的生命为代价
Can you really trust these men
相信这些家伙?
With her life?
是的
Yeah.
没错 我相信是的
Yeah, I believe I can.
好吧 詹姆斯
All right, James.
但还有些关于时间的问题
But there's been some confusion
最后通牒的时间变了
About the timing of things last-minute changes,
还有
Et cetera.
我得把这事和所有牵连的人说清楚
I'm gonna make this clear for everyone involved.
如果到时间 我还没有
If time runs out and I don't have
拿到另外一半坐标的话
The second half of those coordinates,
LJ还有那小妞
Lj and the senorita
都得死
Stop breathing.
说再见吧 宝贝
Say good-bye, sweetheart.
林肯 林肯
Lincoln Linc
别傻了 林肯
Don't be stupid, Lincoln.
我帮了你的忙了
I've helped you.
现在轮到你帮我了
Now you help me.
拜托了
Please.
拜托把我们带出去
Just get us out of here.
你确认备用发电器的间隔时间没问题?
You sure about t timing on the backup generator?
是的 我们现在所要做的就是
Yeah. all we got to do now
切断外部照明的电源
Is cut the power to the exterior lights.
你怎么才能做到?
How are you gonna do that?
我办不到 内部是没法搞定的
I'm not it can't be accessed from the inside.
我有多少时间?
How much time have I got?
明早5:15
Let's say, uh, 5:15 tomorrow morning.
我们还有足够的时间
That should give us enough time
在日出前挖通隧道
To dig out the tunnel before the sun comes up.
-好吧 那惠斯勒咋办? -怎么说?
All right. what about Whistler? what about him?
他表现的很男人 他本可以
Well, he manned up he could've handed over
交出坐标了事的 但他没有这么做
The information, but he didn't.
还考虑把他交出去吗?
Still concerned about handing him over?
林肯 我差不多为每个人都有考虑
I've got my concerns about pretty much everybody, Linc.
你知道我的意思
You know what I mean?
是的
Yeah.
我只是厌倦了
Mostly, I'm just tired.
厌倦了做选择
Tired of choices
考虑后果
Consequences.
我只想快点结束 就在今晚
I just want this to be over tonight.
我们加油干吧
Let's do it.
当你在跑步(注 双关语 也作逃亡)之时
When you're on the run,
你一直盯着自己的肩头看
You're always looking over your shoulder,
听着警报声
Listinenfor the sirens,
彷徨于
Wondering if that
漂亮姑娘是否有盯着你看
Pretty girl across the street is staring at you
因为她需要你
Because she wants you,
或者就是你被通缉了
Or because you're wanted.
你改名换姓
You change your name,
改头换面
The way you look
抛弃过往的一切
And leave everything you ever knew behind.
包括你爱的人
And the ones you love,
他们是你必须回报的人
They're the ones who have to pay.
是他们在外面等着你
That's what's waiting for you on the outside.
这就是我不能带上你的原因
That's why I couldn't bring you on.
因为这一切不会有什么好下场
Because nothing good can come of this.
继续呆下去会有什么好下场?
Can anything good come from staying in?
这需要你自己做决断
It has to be your decision.
我
I
我不能对你负责
I cannot be responsible for you.
你无需对我负责
You won't have to be.
你爸还保留着上次给你的电话号吗?
Does your father still have that phone number I gave you?
我想是的
I think so.
好吧 让他给我兄弟打电话
Well, tell him to call my brother
如果他想知道明天去哪里接你
If he wants to find out where to pick you up tomorrow.
这就是说
Does that mean
就是说如果一切顺利的话
It means if a million things fall into place
我明天就能见到我爸爸了
I'm gonna see my father tomorrow.
别让任何人看到你打电话
Don't let anyone see you with that phone.
迈克 我想我们搞定了
I think we did it, Michael.
我相信都准备妥了
I believe we're ready.
洞虽然有点湿 但是可以上了
She's a little wet, but she's ready.
让我想到了出去后
Makes me think of the first thing
第一件要干的事情
I'll do when we're gonna get out.
有谁知道西班牙语"别开枪"怎么说?
Just, does anybody know what's spanish for"don't shoot"?
No dispare (注 西班牙语 别开枪)
No dispare.
"No dis"什么?
No dis what?
放松点 没人会被射杀的
Just relax. nobody's gonna get shot.
别紧张
Just don't panic.
林肯一切断电源 我们就走
As soon as Linc cuts the power, we go.
那怎么对付巡逻吉普车怎么对付?
What about the jeep patrol?
已经解决了
Taken care of.
那后备发电机呢?
What about the backup generator?
后备发电机
Backup generator?
没人提及过呀
Nobody said anything about
在后备电源恢复供电前
There's a lag from when the power
会有个真空期
Cuts out to when the nerator kicks back in.
这个真空期有多久?
Well, how long a lag are we talking about here?
30秒钟
30 seconds.
你认为我们30秒钟能跑出去?
You expect us to run in 30 seconds?
灯一熄灭 我就出发
As soon as the lights go out, I'm gone.
去不去随你
With or without you.
朋友 求你了
Please, my friends.
他们还在等着我呢
They're expecting me and
兄弟 我有个坏消息
I have some bad news, Jorge
我们今天付不了你工钱了
We won't be able to pay you today.
没关系 我可以等
That's fine. I-I can wait until
当我们结账处理的时候 查到你身份
When we ran your identification through processing
发现了个小问题
we found a slight problem
什么问题?
What kind of a problem?
你有赦免令才免于被拘捕
You have warrant out for your arrest.
就现在
Now.
行动
Let's go.
下车 快
Off the bus now
都下车
Get off the bus
只要灯一灭 我们就准备好离开
As soon as the lights go out, we got to be ready to move.
这小兔崽子来这里干什么?
You want to tell us what the hell the taquito's doing down here?
-他和我们一起走 -我可没答应
He's coming with us. I don't think so.
这不管你的事
That's not up to you.
我觉得我该管
I should I think.
你居然还瞎折腾
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
我们已经另外做好了打算
See, we made up our own decision here.
因为时间
Well, with the time frame
是这样的短暂
Being so short and all,
我们觉得先走一步 会好很多
We'd feel a whole lot better about things if we go first.
你会怎么做 杀了我?
What are you gonna do, kill me?
不 不会 听着 如果我们不先走
No, no. see, if we ain't first,
-他也根本走不了 -行了
He's not going at all all right.
够了
All right just
听着 我可以解释这一切
Look, I think I can explain all this.
如果你让我去车里取文书的话
If I could just get some paperwork from my car
你哪儿也去不了
You're not going anywhere.
听明白了吗?
Understand?
好吧
All right.
好吧 走 走啊
All right, go. just go.
快走啊
Just go.
人不为己 天诛地灭是吧?
Every man for himself, right?
你也想排队上去 是吧?
You want to move up in line, too?
不 我会守在最后
No, I think I'm gonna stay back he.
我只是不愿意把后背暴露给任何人
I just don't want to turn my back on anybody.
30秒钟时间
30 seconds.
快走
Go.